Remember when I had a monkey?
我之前不是養過猴子？
What was I thinking?
我在想什麼？
Hey,so,what's with the 20 percent tip? Did I do something wrong?
小費怎麼才二十分？ 我做錯事了嗎？
20 percent is a pretty generous tip.
二十分很大方了
You know what's more generous? 50 percent!
你知道幾分更大方？五十分
-You know what's even more generous? -I see where you're going.
你知道怎樣更大方？ 我知道你想說什麼了
What's up with the greed?
你幹嘛這麼貪？
I'm sorry.
好吧，對不起，只是…
I have to get new headshots made, and they're really expensive.
我得照新的大頭照，但是好貴
I'm down to,like,three.
我只剩三張了
Actually,two, because one of them I blackened some teeth.
其實是兩張，有一張的牙齒 被我塗黑…
Why'd I do that?
我秀逗啊
Isn't there something you can do to earn extra money?
你不能設法多賺一點嗎？
Can't you pick up an extra shift here?
例如在這裡多輪一班
Or,you know,I used to beg for money.
或是我以前當過乞丐
It helps if you've got a little of this going on.
如果能這樣更有用
Wow! I still have it.
我現在還會
Don't you have an audition today? Maybe you'll get that job.
等等，你今天不是有試鏡？ 也許你會入選
Wait a minute.
等等
I used to get medical experiments done on me.
我以前常參加醫學實驗
Finally,an explanation.
難怪變成這樣
I used to get paid for all kinds of medical stuff.
不是，我以前常靠這個賺錢 記得嗎？
Let's see... Well,I don't want to donate sperm again.
我想想，我不想再捐精了
I really prefer doing that at the home office.
那種事在家做比較好
Maybe they want some of my blood or spit or something,huh?
也許醫院會要我的血或口水
-Joey? -Yeah.
喬伊？ 怎樣？
What did I tell you about talking while working?
我說工作時跟朋友聊天會怎樣
Do it?
幹得好？
That guy's been waiting 10 minutes. He's complained about you three times.
那個人等咖啡等了10分鐘 他抱怨了你三次
Now,where was l?
我講到哪裡？
The One With Unagi
本集播出：「鰻魚力量」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
What are you up to?
你們在忙什麼？
We went to a self-defense class today.
我們今天去學防身術
Kicking a guy in the crotch all morning really takes it out of you.
對，踢了一早上的鼠蹊部 什麼鳥氣都沒了
Takes it out of you?
那是你們
Now we can kick anybody's ass.
現在我們誰都能修理
After one class? I don't think so.
才一堂課？不會吧
You want to see me self-defend myself?
你想看我自衛嗎？
Pretend you're a predator.
去假裝你是性侵犯
Go on,I dare you!
有種就去
Of course you can defend yourself from an attack you know is coming.
你當然可以抵擋已知的攻擊
That's not enough.
但那樣還不夠
Look,I studied karate for a long time.
我學了很久的空手道
And there's a concept you should be familiar with.
有個概念你們一定要瞭解
It's what the Japanese call unagi.
日文叫做unagi
Isn't that a kind of sushi?
那不是一種壽司嗎？
No,it's a concept.
那是一種概念
Yeah,it is. It's freshwater eel.
是壽司沒錯，那是鰻魚
Maybe it means that too.
或許是同一個字…
I would kill for a salmon-skin roll right now.
我現在好想吃鮭魚握壽司
Fine,get attacked. I don't even care.
好，被攻擊活該，我不在乎
Come on,Ross,we're sorry. Please tell us what it is.
羅斯，對不起，快告訴我們
Unagi is a state of total awareness.
Unagi是一種全知的境界
Only by achieving true unagi...
只有達到真正的unagi
can you be prepared for any danger that may befall you.
才能應付任何可能的危險
In case someone's trying to steal your bamboo sleeping mat...
你是說有人要偷你的竹蓆
or your kettle of fish?
或魚壺的時候嗎？
It's one thing being prepared for an attack against each other.
我是說應付彼此攻擊是一回事
Whole other story being prepared for an attack. I don't know.. Surprise!
應付偷襲又是另一回事
You knew that was coming...
好，這次你們料到了
but that doesn't mean you have unagi.
但不表示你們有unagi
If we made reservations, we could have unagi in a half-hour.
知道嗎？如果我們現在訂位 半小時後就能吃到鰻魚
-Is Monica here? -No.
摩妮卡在嗎？ 不在
I need help. I don't know what to get for Valentine's Day.
幫個忙 我不知道該送什麼情人節禮物
Valentine's Day was two weeks ago, so I wouldn't get her a calendar.
情人節已經過兩星期了 我不會送她日曆
She was working, so we're celebrating tonight.
她那天要上班，我們改今天過
Why don't you book a day for both of you at those romantic spas?
去幫你們一起訂個SPA嘛
That's actually a good idea.
喬伊，這個主意很棒
And,of course,crotchless panties.
還有胯下開洞的內褲
As appealing as that sounds to her boyfriend...
雖然她的男朋友覺得很誘人…
and her brother...
她哥哥也是
We promised to make each other gifts this year.
但我們說好今年要自己做禮物
-I love that. -You guys!
我喜歡 真好
You can't make crotchless panties?
你不會做開洞的內褲？
You take scissors and cut..
拿一把剪刀給它剪…
Okay,okay,okay.
好好好
Making things sounds so much fun.
做禮物，聽起來好好玩
I thought so too,until I papier-mached one of my eyes shut.
我也這麼認為 直到我的眼睛糊到紙黏土
I love papier-mache! What did you make?
我喜歡紙黏土，你做了什麼？
I made a flar-lar-lar.
我做了@#% ！
-What is that? -Nothing!
那是什麼？ 什麼也不是
So,what are you gonna do?
你要怎麼辦？
Have you made anything I can take credit for?
你們有沒有做什麼能借給我用
I have,I have! I started making little sock bunnies!
我有！我有！我做了襪子兔
Oh,for crying out loud!
了不起吧
Wait a minute. That is my sock!
等等，那是我的襪子
Now it's your little bunny friend.
現在它是你的兔兔朋友
Okay...
好
This actually is a flar-lar-lar.
這是一個@#% ！
Can I ask about the Valentine's Day gifts?
我能不能問你情人節禮物的事
-Yeah. -Do we have to make the entire thing?
可以啊 全都要自己做嗎？
Yes. Did you forget to make yours?
當然，你忘了做嗎？
Of course not.
當然沒有
I just have to go to the place where I made it and pick it up.
我只是得去做的地方拿回來 好
I can't wait. It'll be the best Valentine's Day ever!
我好期待 這會是最棒的情人節
I can't believe it! Make the presents!
我居然忘了，要做禮物
-What? -Just so excited to make the presents!
什麼？ 要做禮物好興奮喔
真是的
Hi,I'm Joey Tribbiani.
你好，我是喬伊崔比亞尼
With all due respect, I'd like to donate some fluids.
我想捐贈一些體液
We're at the end of a research cycle and not looking for applicants now.
我們的研究剛告一段落 目前沒有在找人
That's too bad. I've been saving up.
真可惜，我存了一陣子
You sure there's no studies I can participate in?
真的沒有我能參加的研究？
-Here's a schedule. -Thanks.
這是接下來的一覽表 謝謝
This one starts now.
這個已經開始了
Only identical twins are eligible. It's a twin study.
沒錯，但只限雙胞胎 那是雙胞胎研究
But it's $2000!
但是有2千塊錢
Sorry.
抱歉
And this?
那...
"Testing the Effects of Joey Tribbiani on Attractive Nurse Receptionist."
喬伊崔比亞尼 對美女接待的影響力實驗呢？
Results are back on that one. They're not good.
結果已經出來了，不太理想
-That was good. -Yeah.
Danger! Danger!
危險！危險
What the hell was that?
你搞什麼啊？
A lesson in the importance of unagi.
讓你們認識unagi的重要
You're a freak!
你變態
Perhaps.
或許吧
Now I'm curious.
我很好奇
At what point during those girlish screams would you have kicked my ass?
你們那樣哀哀叫 什麼時候才要修理我？
All right, so we weren't prepared!
好吧，我們沒有準備
I'm sorry I had to take such drastic measures to make my point.
抱歉用這種方法傳達我的重點
I just want you to be safe.
我是為你們的安全著想
Danger!
危險！
Ah-ha!
Unagi!
Unagi
「選角經紀公司」
2000 bucks is a lot of money.
2千塊好多
I wish I had a twin.
真想有個雙胞胎兄弟
Where could I find someone...
哪裡才有...
who looks exactly like me?
跟我長得一樣的人？
Chandler.
錢德
I sensed it was you.
我感覺到是你
What?
什麼？
Unagi.
Unagi
I'm always aware.
我永遠全知
Are you aware that unagi is an eel?
你知道unagi是鰻魚嗎？
-What's up? -I can't figure out what to make Monica.
什麼事？ 我不知道該做什麼禮物
Why don't you make her one of your little jokes?
你可以講個笑話
I'm going crazy. Do you have anything homemade?
我快急死了，好嗎？ 你有沒有狀似自製的東西？
You know what? She'd love this.
這個她一定會喜歡
It's a replica of Apollo 8. I made it in the sixth grade.
這是阿波羅八號的模型 我六年級做的
I could use that. I could say, "Your love sends me to the moon."
這個可以 我可以說你的愛讓我飛上月亮
Except Apollo 8 didn't actually land on the moon.
可是阿波羅八號沒有登陸月球
You can say, "Your love lets me orbit the moon twice and return safely."
不過你可以寫你的愛 讓我繞行月球兩圈後順利返航
I can't give this to her.
我不能送這個 為什麼？
-Why not? -It says "Captain Ross" on the side.
因為旁邊寫著「羅斯隊長」
And it says "I hate Monica" on the bottom.
底下寫著「我討厭摩妮卡」
Danger!
危險！
Salmon-skin roll.
鮭魚握壽司
好…
Yes,honey, I made it myself.
沒錯，這是我自己做的
I can't do it. I can't do it.
我剪不下去，我剪不下去
A mixed tape! A mixed tape!
自己錄的合輯
Hi! Ready to exchange gifts?
可以交換禮物了嗎？
-Sure. You go first. -Okay,come here.
當然，你先 好，過來
Okay, it's not wrapped because I just finished it.
好 我沒有包裝，因為我剛完成 好
But I made you a tape of what I think are all romantic songs.
我錄了一捲浪漫情歌給你
What a great gift!
好棒的禮物
Is "The Way You Look Tonight" on it?
有「你今晚的模樣」嗎？
We'll have to listen and see.
聽了就知道
Oh,I love it! Thank you so much.
我好喜歡喔，謝謝你 不客氣
You ready to open yours?
你要拆了嗎？ 要
It's a sock bunny.
是襪子兔
Remember how I call you bunny?
對，我不是有叫你小兔兔？
Not really.
有嗎？
I did one time. And I want to start doing it more.
我叫過一次，以後我想多叫
-That's what this is about. -I see.
所以做了襪子兔 我懂了
Phoebe makes sock bunnies.
菲比也有做襪子兔
No,she doesn't. What she makes,they're sock rabbits.
不，沒有 菲比做的是襪子兔子
They're completely different. Okay,okay.
完全不一樣…好吧
I didn't make it!
這不是我做的
I forgot about tonight and that we're supposed to make the presents.
我完全忘了今晚和做禮物的事
It's okay.
沒關係，我…
No,it's not okay.
不，當然有關係
You're so incredible.
你那麼…你那麼用心
You went through all this time and effort to make this tape.
花那麼多心血錄情歌給我
I'll make this up to you. I will.
我要補償你，我一定會的
I am going to cook you anything you want in here.
我會下廚房煮你想吃的菜
And I'm going to do anything you want in there.
進臥房玩你想玩的花樣
Well, I did put a lot of thought into the tape.
我的確花了很多心血
You are way too young to have seen that.
你還小，不該看的
Your birthday's in a month and a half.
再1個半月就是你的生日
What if I forget to get you a present for that too?
要是我又忘記準備禮物呢？
You are totally and completely 100 percent forgiven.
我百分之百完全原諒你
We've got to wash that.
那個得拿去洗 沒錯
Remember that jacket you loved that was too expensive?
你不是看上一件外套 又嫌它太貴？
You have done enough.
你對我已經夠好了
I'll wake up early and get it.
我要一早跑去買來送你
No,you don't.. Get it in black,not brown.
你不必… 買黑色，別買咖啡色
Your cake is ready.
你的蛋糕好了
It's like that old saying, "Have sex, eat some cake."
俗話說得好 做做愛，吃吃蛋糕
Hey,Mon. Hey,Chan. Just getting a soda.
小摩，老錢，我來拿汽水
Who the hell are you?
你是誰？
I'm Joey.
喬伊啊
How are you doing?
你好嗎？
No! No! No! No! No!
錯錯錯錯錯！
How you doing?
是你好嗎
How you doing? Damn it, Carl! Go wait in the hall.
你好嗎…真是的！去走廊等我
I've got to apologize on behalf of Carl.
我代替卡爾道歉
Who the hell is Carl?
卡爾是誰？
Did I not mention?
我沒說嗎？
Carl is a guy I hired to be my twin for a medical research project.
我找卡爾來演我的雙胞胎兄弟 好參加醫學研究
Sometimes the good ideas are right in front of you.
有時妙計就在眼前，是吧？
It sounds crazy, but it might work. The only problem is Carl's acting...
我知道很扯，但搞不好會成功 唯一的問題是卡爾的演技…
The only problem?
唯一的問題？
He's the reason I didn't get that big commercial a couple of years ago.
對，他害我兩年前 痛失那支大廣告，記得嗎？
We were supposed to be brothers, but he messed up.
我們演兄弟，他卻搞砸了
Can I get a piece of that cake?
我可以吃一小塊蛋糕嗎？
Pizza! We like pizza! Get out!
披薩，我們愛吃披薩 滾出去
-Pat Sajak? -Yep.
派特賽賈克？ 可以
-Alex Trebek? -Of course.
亞歷崔貝克？ 當然
-Chuck Woolery? -Definitely.
恰克烏勒利？ 絕對行
You will not find a single game-show host whose ass I cannot kick.
所有的綜藝節目主持人 我都能修理
-Say it! -Say we are unagi!
說 說我們是unagi
It's not something you are, it's something you have.
不是是不是，而是有沒有
Say it!
快說
I could easily get out of this...
我可以輕易掙脫
but there's a chance you could get very, very hurt!
但你們可能會死得很慘
Carl,we're next. Now remember, what is this not gonna be?
接著就是我們 記住，這次不能怎樣？
-Another Minute Maid fiasco. -That's right.
重蹈那次廣告的覆轍 沒錯
And what are you not gonna do?
你不能怎樣？
-I'm not gonna talk because.. -Damn it,Carl!
我不能講話，因為… 你還講
惦惦
Can I have the next one,please?
下一組的資料…
Thank you.
謝謝
Joey and Tony Tribbiani.
喬伊和湯尼崔比亞尼
That's us.
我們就是
But this is a study for identical twins.
這是雙胞胎的研究
That's right. $2000.
沒錯，2千大洋
But you're not identical twins.
但你們不是雙胞胎
Damn it, Carl!
都是你啦
Oh, my good God.
我的天哪
Continuing the countdown of your favorite meals.
你最愛吃的食物倒數
Tonight, number three:
今晚，第三名
Macaroni and cheese with cut-up hot dogs.
起司通心粉加切丁的熱狗
Look,you have done enough. You have to stop this now.
你對我夠好了，別再費心了
I will,but not tonight.
我會的，但不是今晚
For dinner music, I thought we could listen to that tape that you made me.
晚餐音樂就來聽你錄的帶子
Oh, the mixed tape.
那卷合輯
"The Way You Look Tonight" is on here.
剛好就是「你今晚的模樣」
Dance with me.
陪我跳舞
You are just the sweetest.
你最好最好了
I love the way you look every night, Chandler.
你每晚的模樣我都愛，錢德
That's why I made you this tape.
所以我錄這卷帶子給你
Happy birthday! Love,Janice!
生日快樂，愛你的珍妮絲
No,you're the sweetest.
不，你最好最好了
Okay, ladies, that ends today's class.
好，今天的課到此為止
Remember,be safe out there.
記住，一定要平安
-Great class. -Thanks.
你教得真好 謝謝
I was watching.
我看得很仔細
A couple of questions:
不過我有一些問題
You know that last move...
剛才最後...
where that woman tripped you and pinned you to the floor?
那個女人把你絆倒 壓在地上
What would you do next?
你接下來會怎麼做？
She'd take the keys and jam them in your..
她會拿鑰匙來刺…
No,no. What would you do next?
不是，是你會怎麼做？
-Who,me,the attacker? -Yes,that's right.
你是說攻擊者？ 是的
Why?
幹嘛？
I tried attacking two women. Did not work.
我想偷襲兩個女人，卻沒成功
What?
什麼？
No,it's okay. They're my friends.
沒關係，她們是我的朋友
In fact,I was married to one of them.
我還跟其中一個結過婚
You attacked your ex-wife?
你偷襲你的前妻？
Oh,no. No,no.
不是…
I tried.
我想偷襲她
But I couldn't. That's why I'm here.
卻打不過她，所以才來找你
Maybe we could attack them together!
或許我們可以一起對付她們
That's a no.
你不要
I am so,so,so,so sorry.
非常非常非常對不起
And I will cook anything you want in here...
我會下廚房煮你想吃的菜
and do anything you want in there.
進臥房玩你想玩的花樣
Yeah,you will! And are you kidding me?
你當然得煮，你想得美喔
Come on,Monica, it's our Valentine's Day.
別這樣，這是我們的情人節
Please,please,please,please?
拜託啦？
Okay.
好吧
我有趣的情人 甜蜜逗趣的情人
-So are we going in there? -I am!
要進房間了嗎？ 我要
你的表情如此有趣
Nowhere to run.
你們逃不掉了
I don't like sitting up here. I'm gonna go over..
我不喜歡坐這裡，我要過去…
No,they got here first.
是他們先來的
-Why is Ross doing that? -Danger!
羅斯在幹嘛？ 危險！
Oh,my God! Why is he jumping on those women?
天哪 他幹嘛撲向那兩個女人？
We should help them.
我們應該去幫她們
I don't think they need any help.
我看她們不需要幫忙